<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Ivaylo Ivanov</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Ivaylo Ivanov</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 11:27:50 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adventures with the Volla Phone Quintus - part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/quintus-hacking-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 11:27:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/quintus-hacking-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;initial-efforts&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Initial efforts&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#initial-efforts&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Following the standard procedure, I first started by unlocking the phone bootloader, which was easy. I flashed a verity disabled vbmeta and I was ready to start experimenting with custom boot images.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LK expects a gzipped kernel image and a valid dtb that it can append a dtbo to. Unfortunately, the device has two very annoying quirks:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LK has its own device tree and needs to apply the dtbo. That means you can&amp;rsquo;t just erase the dtbo partition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The dtbo has 300 lines of required nodes for LK to boot, which means that making it apply to a mainline device tree will be ugly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the approach I&amp;rsquo;m taking is to use a secondary bootloader (loaded as a kernel image by LK), which later on can boot mainline linux without the ugliness.&#xA;This is the command I used to make a boot image:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the reason behind the infamous S22 boot loops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/s22-bootloop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 20:10:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/s22-bootloop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As some of you may know, there&amp;rsquo;s been quite a lot of issues with the S22 lineup - from screen defects appearing out of nowhere to phones suddenly starting to crash and boot loop, with close to no information regarding the issues apart from posts here and there. If you don&amp;rsquo;t want to read about specifics of how I found the problem and how I fixed it (in a way that&amp;rsquo;s not not preferable), skip to the end of the post for a conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Mainline Linux to life on ATM7051 handhelds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/powkiddy-x51/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 18:48:50 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/powkiddy-x51/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;mainline-linux-on-the-powkiddy-x51&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Mainline Linux on the Powkiddy X51&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#mainline-linux-on-the-powkiddy-x51&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, the Mainline Linux kernel (upstream) is the newest released and under-development version of the Linux kernel. Quite literally: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/torvalds/linux&#34;&gt;github.com/torvalds/linux&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;a-bit-of-history&#34;&gt;&#xA;  A bit of history&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#a-bit-of-history&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on SoC and device bringup as a Linux kernel hobbyist for a while now (~4 years). One or two years ago, I got my hands on a handheld called Powkiddy X51, because why not :D.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 18:47:52 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/portfolio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;linux&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Linux&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#linux&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Powkiddy X51 handheld console is relatively hard to develop mainline Linux for, because there are no official kernel sources, nor any kind of documentations for this platform. Both Powkiddy and Actions Semiconductor ignored all my emails, so a lot of things had to be reverse-engineered. Thankfully there also ancient kernel sources for a somewhat similar platform, from where I can borrow information about some registers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are still some essential things that have to be brought up. For example:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
